你会喜欢特拉弗准将的
You'll enjoy Commodore Travers.
他很善于吃
He sets a good table.
我不知道他会不会把他的厨师长也带到塞斯图斯三号星上
I wonder if he brought his personal chef along with him to Cestus III.
或许吧，军衔总是附有特权
Probably. Rank hath its privileges.
我们对此非常了解啊
How well we both know that, huh?
史考特
Scotty.
- 我是寇克 - 我是特拉弗，吉姆，我们在等你呢
- Kirk here. - Travers, Jim. we're waiting.
好的，准将，我们正在路上
Good, commodore. We're on our way.
一定要带上你的战术小组
Be sure to bring along your tactical people.
这里有些有趣的事情
I've got an interesting problem for them.
准将，我们会立刻传送下去，通话结束
We'll beam down immediately, commodore. Kirk out.
船长，我好奇为什么
Captain, I wonder why
他那么坚持要我们的战术副官也降落到地面
he's so insistent that our tactical aides come down.
这块殖民地是孤立的，暴露在外，周遭空无一物
This colony is isolated, exposed, out on the edge of nowhere.
他或许需要额外的建议
He probably wants additional advice.
或许是这样吧，船长，然而，我--
Perhaps, captain, but nevertheless, I--
史波克，准将以好客出名，这理由还不够吗？
Spock, isn't it enough the commodore is famous for his hospitality?
就比如我，很乐意吃上一顿不是压缩粮食的饭
I, for one, could use a good nonreconstituted meal.
医生，你真是个感官主义者
Doctor, you are a sensualist.
用你的尖耳朵打赌，我就是的
You bet your pointed ears I am.
船长，准备好传送了
Ready whenever you are, captain.
通电
Energize.
- 寇克呼叫进取号，红色警告 - 船长，发生什么事了？
- Kirk to Enterprise. Red alert. - What is it, captain?
塞斯图斯三号已经被摧毁了
Cestus III has been destroyed.
宇宙，最后的边疆
Space, the final frontier.
这是星舰进取号的航程
These are the voyages Of the starship Enterprise.
它的五年任务，是去探索未知的新世界
Its five-year mission: To explore strange, new worlds,
找寻新的生命与新的文明
to seek out new life and new civilizations,
勇敢的航向前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
【星际迷航：原初】
-=THE LAST FANTASY=-
荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=TLF字幕组=-
翻译：sholto Nick
校对：Micezhang
第一季第十八集
竞技场
全面警戒
Full alert.
史波克先生，三录仪检测，生命探测
Tricorder readings, Mr. Spock. Life detection.
船长，昨天那条指引我们来这里的消息--
Those messages we got, captain, the one directing us here yesterday--
是假的，这里的一切发生在几天前
Faked. All this happened several days ago.
朗，去那边，寻找生还者
Lang, over there. Look for survivors.
凯洛维茨，去那边
Kelowitz, that way.
欧赫里希，跟着我
O'Herlihy, stick with me.
船长，脉冲出现在那个方向
Captain, impulses that direction.
非常微弱，或许是个生还者
Very weak, possibly a survivor.
来吧，老骨头
Come on, Bones.
船长日志，星历3045.6
Captain's log, stardate 3045.6.
进取号收到了一个
The Enterprise has responded to a call
来自塞斯图斯三号地面观测前哨站的信息
from Earth observation outpost on Cestus III.
一登陆，我们就发现这个前哨站已经被摧毁了
On landing, we have discovered that the outpost has been destroyed.
船长，在那里
Captain, over there.
轻点，轻点
- Careful. - Careful.
受到惊吓，辐射灼伤
Shock, radiation burns,
肯定有内伤，船长，他情况很糟糕
internal injuries for certain. He's in a bad way, captain.
老骨头，保住他的性命，我要知道这里发生了什么
Keep him alive, Bones. I want to know what's been happening here.
船长，又发现了一个生命迹象
Getting another life reading, captain.
- 是幸存者吗？ - 不是幸存者
- Survivors? - Not survivors.
不是热血生物
Not warm-blooded.
是活着的生物，但不是人
Living creatures, but not human.
在哪里？
Where?
方位角，93度，距离，1570码
Azimuth, 93 degrees. Range, 1570 yards.
欧赫里希
O'Herlihy.
船长，我看见一些东西
Captain, I see something.
找掩护
Cover.
寇克呼叫进取号，锁定传送器，把我们传送上去
Kirk to Enterprise. Lock on transporters. Beam us up.
船长，我们被袭击了，不明身份的飞船向我们逼近
Captain, we're coming under attack. Unidentified ship quartering in.
无法传送你们，我刚启动好防御屏障
We can't beam you up. I've just rigged up defensive screens.
保持屏障开启，发射所有相位炮
Keep those screens up. Fire all phasers.
船长，正发射相位炮
Firing phasers, captain.
那艘船也开启屏障了
The alien has screens up too.
采取一切必要措施保护星舰
Take all action necessary to protect the ship.
我们会坚守在这里
We'll hold out here.
船长，你也受到攻击了吗？
Are you under attack, captain?
- 我们可以关闭屏障 - 一定要保持屏障开启
- We could drop screens. - Keep those screens up.
当星舰安全的时候再担心我们吧
Worry about us when the ship is safe.
通话结束
Kirk out.
如果他们撤销防御屏障来传送我们上去
If they lower those screens to beam us up,
他们也会暴露在激光攻击之下
they'll be open to phaser attack.
船长，我们悲剧地不够兵力
We're hopelessly outnumbered here, captain.
他们的裂解炮对抗我们的相位手枪…
Those disrupters versus our hand phasers...
史波克先生，我们情况不妙
We're stuck with it, Mr. Spock.
我们一定要利用好现有的一切
We'll have to make do with what we've got.
凯洛维茨，朗，由侧翼出去
Kelowitz, Lang, flank out.
对着史波克先生给你们的坐标开火
Lay down fire on coordinates Mr. Spock gave you.
即使你们看不到他们，也要万分小心
Even if you don't see them. Keep your heads down.
我们在这里毫无希望
Helpless down here.
进取号--
And the Enterprise--
船长，苏鲁是个经验丰富的战斗指挥官
Sulu is an experienced combat officer, captain.
史波克先生，那是我的船，我该在那里的
It's my ship, Mr. Spock. I should be there.
我们甚至不能射中他们
We can't even get at them.
他们现在也不能射中我们
Nor can they at us, at the moment.
除非他们从原来的位置移开
Not unless they move their original position.
移到那中间的高地
That intervening high ground.
你还记得这个地方的布局吗？军械库？
You remember the layout of this place? The arsenal?
大约在那个方向100码处
About 100 yards in that direction.
但承受了和这里一样的攻击后--
But after an attack as thorough as this one--
我去试试看
I'll risk it.
我是寇克，向我报告
Kirk here. Report.
船长，你还好吧？
Captain, are you all right?
不要担心我，星舰怎么样了？
Never mind about me. What about the ship?
我们用所有的相位炮组向对方开火
We returned fire with all phaser banks.
但是对它的偏导防御屏障无效
Negative against its deflector screen.
- 配备光子鱼雷 - 是的，长官
- Arm your photon torpedoes. - Aye, aye, sir.
已配备光子鱼雷，正在待命
Arm photon torpedoes. Stand by.
有攻击舰的身份证明吗？
Any identification on the attacking vessel?
没有，长官，和我们熟悉的任何构造都不相符
No, sir. Doesn't correspond with any configuration we're familiar with.
我们不能建立可视通话，它离我们太远了
We can't get visual contact. She's too far away.
苏鲁先生，光子鱼雷锁定
Mr. Sulu, photon torpedoes locked on.
船长，光子鱼雷已锁定
Photon torpedoes locked on, captain.
所有炮组发射
Fire all banks.
长官，所有炮组已发射
All banks fired, sir.
苏鲁
Sulu.
苏鲁，我们的通话被干扰了
Sulu, our communications are being interfered with.
现在，长话短说：
Now, get this straight:
采取任何你认为必须的手段保护星舰
Do anything you think necessary to protect the ship.
离开运行轨道，最大曲速度，任何事，你明白了吗？
Leave orbit, maximum warp, anything. Clear?
明白了，船长，但是你--
Clear, captain. But you--
不要担心我，保护好我的船
Never mind about me. Protect my ship.
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
船长，光子鱼雷无效
Photon torpedoes negative, captain.
我要用曲速脱离轨道
I'm warping out of orbit.
好的
Good.
随时联系我，通话完毕
Contact me when you can. Kirk out.
医生，他怎样了？
How is he, doctor?
如果不对他进行妥善治疗，他将在半小时内死亡
He'll be dead in half an hour if we don't get him some decent care.
他们在转移，我要去找船长
They're moving. I've got to get to the captain.
船长，我已经锁定敌人了
I've locked on to the enemy, captain.
他们正移动到高地
They're moving toward the high ground.
他们也锁定了我的三录仪
They've locked on to my tricorder.
非常巧妙，他们反馈我自己的脉冲，让我的探测器过载了
Very ingenious. They fed back my own impulses and built up an overload.
我们来看看他们究竟有多巧妙
We'll see how ingenious they are.
给你，帮我固定住这个榴弹炮支架
Here, give me a hand with this grenade launcher.
朗！
Lang!
进取号怎样了？
Any word from the Enterprise?
苏鲁让它脱离轨道了
Sulu's taken her out of orbit.
长官，他们击中朗了
They got Lang, sir.
- 你看见他们了吗？ - 没有，长官
- Did you see them? - No, sir.
凯洛维茨先生，估计下，你认为他们在哪儿？
An evaluation, Mr. Kelowitz. Where do you think they are?
如果我是他们，我会去右边的高地
If I were them, I'd go to the high ground on the right.
我认为那个位置离我们1200码，方位角87度
I'd make it 1,200 yards. Azimuth 87.
船长，这个位置可离榴弹炮很近
It's pretty close for one of these little jewels, captain.
会离他们更近，你们都靠后
It will be a lot closer to them. Stand clear.
- 我是寇克 - 船长，外星飞船在撤退
- Kirk here. - Captain, the alien is withdrawing.
它离我们很远
She's at extreme range,
但是我们的传感器显示它刚启动了传送器
but our sensors indicate she just activated her transporters.
锁定外星飞船，苏鲁先生，我不会放过它
Lock on to the alien, Mr. Sulu. I don't wanna lose her.
是的，长官
Aye, aye, sir.
我们的防御屏障关闭了，长官，我现在能把你们传送上来了
Our screens are down. We can beam you up now, sir.
我要一支有30名医疗人员的搜查队
I want a search party of 30 medical personnel
立刻传送到地面搜索生还者
beamed down immediately to search for survivors.
通知传送室，锁定我们，我们要传送上去
Notify the Transporter Room. Lock on to us. We're beaming up.
是的，长官
Aye, aye, sir.
船长日志，补充
Captain's log, supplement.
我们已传送回进取号上
We have beamed back to the Enterprise
并立即出发追踪外星飞船
and immediately set out in pursuit of the alien vessel.
它像是航向一大片未被探明的
It appears to be headed towards a largely unexplored
星系区域
section of the galaxy.
你能告诉我发生了什么事吗？
Can you tell me what happened?
扫描仪报告一艘飞船在靠近
Scanners reported a ship approaching.
我们时不时会获取他们的信息
We get them now and then.
我们很欢迎他们使用我们的设施，你知道的，长官
They're all welcome to use our facilities. You know that, sir.
他们来了
They came in,
以正常空间航行速度
space normal speed,
用我们常规的通道
using our regular approach run,
但是他们第一次齐射就击倒了我们的相位电池
but they knocked out our phaser batteries with their first salvo.
从那时起，我们就变得无助了，我们再不期盼任何东西
From then on, we were helpless. We weren't expecting anything!
为什么会是我们？我们又没有什么别人会觊觎的东西
Why should we? We didn't have anything anyone would want!
放松，放松
Easy, easy.
他们铺天盖地地用像是--
They poured it on like--
相位的武器，不管他们使用什么，但更糟
Like phasers, only worse, whatever they were using.
我试着向他们发信号，我们呼喊
I tried to signal them. We called up,
想要投降
tried to surrender.
我告诉他们，我们有妇女和儿童
We had women and children. I told them that.
我请求他们，他们却不听
I begged them. They wouldn't listen.
他们都没暂停一会
They didn't let up for a moment.
上尉
Lieutenant,
进取号收到两条信息
the Enterprise received two messages,
看起来像是来自塞斯图斯三号
ostensibly from Cestus III.
一条是让进取号到达那里
One for the Enterprise to go there
另一条是让我和我的战术小组
and the other for myself and my tactical crew
传送到地面
to beam down to the surface.
船长，在你们到达那里之前，他们袭击了我们一整天
They hit us a full day before you got there, captain.
船长，我们没法送任何信息
No messages came from us, captain.
他们为什么要这样做？
Why did they do it?
为什么？
Why?
他们为什么要这样做？
Why did they do it?
一定是有原因的
There has to be a reason.
- 一定是有原因的 - 这是个圈套
- There has to be a reason! - It was a trap.
让进取号来到塞斯图斯三号
Getting the Enterprise to come to Cestus III.
向我们和我们全体成员发动攻击
Getting us and our whole crew to come ashore.
非常聪明，至于原因--
Very clever. As to the reason--
原因非常清楚
The reason is crystal clear.
进取号是联邦在这个地区唯一的保护措施
The Enterprise is the only protection in this section of the Federation.
摧毁进取号，他们就无人可挡了
Destroy the Enterprise, and everything is wide open.
船长，你暗示他们是在侵略？
You allude to invasion, captain,
但是还没有充分的证据--
yet positive proof has not--
在塞斯图斯三号上我就有了充足的证据
I have all the proof I need on Cestus III.
长官，我们还不能确定，这可以有若干个可能的解释--
Not necessarily, sir. Several possible explanations come--
那你怎么解释像那样的一场屠杀？
How can you explain a massacre like that?
不，史波克先生，他们的威胁是事实清楚、行动迅速的
No, Mr. Spock, the threat is clear and immediate.
这就是侵略
Invasion.
好吧
Very well, then.
如果真是那样的话
If that's the case,
你必须保证将外星飞船摧毁，不让它回到它的基地
you must make certain that the alien vessel never reaches its home base.
我会的
I intend to.
如果我们能把他们赶到我们武力之外的黑暗中
If we can keep them in the dark as to our strength,
它们就不敢行动起来反抗我们
they'll never dare move against us.
- 船长呼叫舵手 - 长官，我是苏鲁
- Captain to helmsman. - sulu here, sir.
- 外星飞船还在以5级曲速航行？ - 是的，长官
- Is the alien still making warp 5? - Affirmative, sir.
- 加速到6级曲速 - 好的，长官
- Initiate warp 6. - Affirmative, sir.
追上它们，准备相位炮组
Overtake. Phaser banks.
锁定外星飞船
Lock on to the enemy vessel.
等待开火命令
Stand by for firing orders.
所有船员，我是船长，我们将要与外星飞船开战
All hands, this is the captain. We are going into battle.
所有船员，战斗岗位
All hands, battle stations.
红色警报，我重复，红色警报，这不是演习
Red alert. I repeat, red alert. This is no drill.
这不是演习
This is no drill.
船长日志，星历3046.2
Captain's log, stardate 3046.2.
我们急速地追赶
We are in hot pursuit
摧毁了塞斯图斯三号上地面前哨站的外星飞船
of the alien vessel which destroyed the Earth outpost on Cestus III.
- 迪保罗先生？ - 是的，长官
- Mr. DePaul? - Yes, sir.
外星飞船的位置
Position.
长官，距上次记录点又航行了20.3秒差 【秒差距：衡量天体间距离的单位】
Twenty-two-point-three parsecs beyond latest chart limit, sir.
所有扫描仪锁进计算机组
All scanners lock into computer banks.
我要全程记录
I want a complete record of this.
史波克先生
Mr. Spock.
你对这个区域了解吗？
What do we have on this general area?
事实上一点也不知道，船长，没有任何探索过的记录
Virtually nothing, captain. No records of any explorations.
有流言说，在子空间频道有某些奇怪的信号
There are rumours of certain strange signals on subspace channels.
但是，从没有被记录过
However, none has ever been recorded.
有没有智慧生命形式？
Anything on intelligent life forms?
船长，不知道
Nothing specific, captain.
只是些没有科学性的流言，更像是太空传说
Unscientific rumours only. More like space legends.
安全控制部，这里是舰桥，情况报告
Security control, this is bridge. Status report.
苏鲁先生，报告外星飞船的状态
Mr. Sulu, status, alien vessel.
长官，他们一定知道了我们在追赶他们
They must be aware we're after them, sir.
他们也加速到6级曲速了
They've gone to warp 6 also.
加速到7级曲速
Warp factor 7.
好的，长官
Aye, aye, sir.
史波克先生，你有什么话要说吗？
Something the matter, Mr. Spock?
船长，持续用7级曲速航行会很危险
A sustained warp-7 speed will be dangerous, captain.
史波克先生，谢谢你的提醒
Thank you, Mr. Spock.
我就是要抓住他们
I mean to catch them.
嗯，船长，要么抓住他们，要么我们自己爆炸
We'll either catch them, or we'll blow up, captain.
他们的速度或许比我们快
They may be faster than we are.
那就拭目以待吧
They'll have to prove it.
有事吗，史波克先生？
Yes, Mr. Spock?
船长，你要摧毁那艘外星飞船吗？
You mean to destroy the alien ship, captain?
当然
Of course.
我认为或许仅仅追赶就已经足够了
I thought perhaps the hot pursuit alone might be sufficient.
彻底摧毁或许没有必要
Destruction may be unnecessary.
史波克先生，塞斯图斯三号殖民地已经被彻底抹去了
Colony Cestus III has been obliterated, Mr. Spock.
吉姆，摧毁外星飞船也于事无补
The destruction of the alien vessel will not help that colony, Jim.
如果这群外星人不受到严惩，他们还会回来
If the aliens go unpunished, they'll be back,
袭击其他的联邦基地
attacking other Federation installations.
我只是建议把他们看做有知觉的生命来理解--
I merely suggest that a regard for sentient life--
没有时间那么做了
There's no time for that.
这是政策问题
It's a matter of policy.
在这里，我们是附近唯一的警察
Out here, we're the only policeman around,
而这里发生了一起罪案，我表述清楚了吗？
and a crime has been committed. Do I make myself clear?
- 很清楚，船长 - 很高兴你能明白，史波克先生
- Very clear, captain. - I'm delighted, Mr. Spock.
苏鲁先生，报告情况
Report, Mr. Sulu.
外星飞船保持着与我们的间隔，船长 现在也在以7级曲速航行
Alien ship maintaining interval, captain. Now at warp 7.
加速到8级曲速
Warp factor 8.
是的，长官
Aye, aye, sir.
船长与相位炮组通话，所有人员临战准备
Captain to phaser banks. All components at battle-ready.
所有炮组装填弹药
All banks primed.
尾部相位炮组与舰桥通话
Aft phaser to bridge.
已处于工作状态，所有武器已做好发射准备
Work status, all weapons at operational ready.
- 船长？ - 苏鲁先生
- Captain? - Yes, Mr. Sulu.
接近目标了，长官
Closing on target, sir.
做得好，迪保罗先生？
Good. Mr. DePaul?
- 长官？ - 我们的位置呢？
- Yes, sir? - Our position?
2279PL，长官
Two-two-seven-nine PL, sir.
在2466PM区域有未记录的太阳系
Uncharted solar system at 2466 PM.
那是外星飞船的航向吗？
This is on the alien's course?
不是，长官，它在远离该太阳系
No, sir. He's headed away from it.
船长，监测部门报告有人在扫描我们
Captain, sensors report we're being scanned.
是那艘外星飞船吗？
By the alien ship?
不是，长官，扫描来自前方的太阳系
No, sir, it's from that solar system ahead.
有什么干扰或者抵抗吗？
Any interference? Resistance?
没有，长官，只是扫描波
No, sir, just scanning beams.
扫描波有一个不同寻常的波长
It's on an unusual wavelength.
史波克先生？
Mr. Spock?
看起来有人对我们很感兴趣
It would appear someone is curious about us.
苏鲁先生，那艘外星飞船还在远离太阳系？
Mr. Sulu, is the alien still heading away from that solar system?
是的，长官，长官，我们接近了
Yes, sir. We're closing, sir.
乌乎拉上尉，对那扫描波有什么进一步的了解吗？
Lieutenant Uhura, anything further on those scanning beams?
长官，它们没有敌意
There's no hostility, sir.
他们没有任何类型的牵引器或者武器
They're not tractors or weapons of any sort,
只是在强度上不断增加
just increasing in intensity.
很稳定
Steady.
很规律，长官，越来越强了
Regular. It's growing stronger, sir.
- 船长！ - 怎么了？
- Captain! - Yes, what is it?
外星飞船，它减速了，5级曲速
The alien, it's slowing down. Warp 5,
4级
4,
2级
2.
长官，要到达亚光速了
It's going sublight, sir.
长官
Sir...
- 它在太空中不动了 - 他或许是要转过头战斗
- It stopped dead in space. - He may be turning to fight.
不，长官，它只是在那不动了
No, sir. They're just dead out there.
你确定吗？
Are you sure?
是的，长官，停止不动
Yes, sir. Unmoving.
那我们逮着它了
Then we've got him.
发布红色警戒，准备发射相位炮组
Go to red alert. Prepare to fire phaser banks.
传感器，锁定外星飞船，苏鲁先生，继续接近
Sensors, lock on. Mr. Sulu, continue closing.
苏鲁先生，将相位炮组锁进电脑
Mr. Spock, lock phasers into computers.
电脑会自动控制攻击
Computers will control attack.
计算机准备就绪，舰长，所有系统已待命
Computer lock ready, captain. All systems standing by.
距离目标1810
Range is 1810,
1760.
距离目标1700
Range is 1700,
1640.
距离目标1590
Range is 1590,
1550，距离还在缩小，舰长
1550 and closing, sir.
6级曲速，5级曲速
Warp 6, warp 5,
4，3级曲速
4, warp 3,
1级曲速
warp 1.
亚光速，舰长
Sublight, captain.
停下来了，舰长，这到底--
We're stopped, captain. It's impossible, but--
AG部，我们这边的读数只有4.5，你们能确认吗？
AG section. we're reading only 4.5 here. Can you confirm?
这是怎么回事？
It's impossible.
突然降了8级曲速，你没搞错吧？
From warp 8, have you lost your mind?
就和敌方星舰一样
Same as the alien, captain.
- 引擎室确认 - AG部确认
- Engine Room acknowledging. - AG section acknowledging.
报告，史考特
Mr. Scott, report.
引擎死火了，舰长，没办法启动
We're dead, captain, locked up. Frozen tight.
- 所有推进系统都停止运作了 - 舰内生命维持系统情况如何？
- All propulsion systems read zero. - Life systems?
都正常，舰长，空气、温度、光线都无变化
They're all normal, sir. Atmosphere, heat, light, no variance.
相位炮组
Phaser banks.
- 汇报情况 - 系统完全停止运作了，舰长
- Report. - We're all inoperative here, captain.
能源供应中断了，没发现故障线路
No power at all. No faulty circuits I can find.
但就是没有能源供应
Just no power.
汇报星舰故障情况
Damage control, report.
所有系统都正常，舰长，没有检查到故障
All systems report normal, captain. No ascertainable damage.
- 那问题出在哪？ - 我不知道，舰长
- Then what is it? - I don't know, sir,
- 但无论如何，我们现在动不了了 - 我们被困住了
- but whatever it is, we cannot move. - We're being held in place, captain.
问题显然来自于那个行星系
Apparently from that solar system.
距离这么远，不可能啊
This far out? That's impossible.
我们被困住了
We are being held.
- 牵引光束？ - 不是的，是一种未知的力量
- Tractor beams? - No, sir. An unidentifiable power.
我们是麦特隆人
We are the Metrons.
你们这两支舰队
You are one of two crafts
怀着暴力意图来到了我们的领地
which have come into our space on a mission of violence.
这是我们不能容忍的
This is not permissible.
但我们也相信
Yet we have analyzed you and have learned
你们的暴力倾向是与生俱来的
that your violent tendencies are inherent.
所以，这样吧
So be it.
让我们来约束你们
We will control them.
化解你们的恩怨
We will resolve your conflict
以最适合你们这些暴戾之徒的方法
in the way most suited to your limited mentalities.
詹姆士·寇克舰长
Captain James Kirk.
我就是寇克
This is Kirk.
我们为你准备了一个合适的星球
We have prepared a planet with a suitable atmosphere.
你将被送往那里
You will be taken there,
你们所追击的敌方舰长也将如此
as will the captain of the Gorn ship which you have been pursuing.
你们将在那里解决纠纷
There you will settle your dispute.
这是什么意思？
I don't understand.
我会给你们提供有转译功能的记录设备
You will be provided with a recording translating device
希望你们的同类在得到这段记录后
in hopes that a chronicle of this contest
不会再侵犯我们的空间
will serve to dissuade others of your kind from entering our system,
但你们将不得与己方舰队联络
but you will not be permitted to communicate with your ship.
必须独自面对这一切
You will each be totally alone.
你凭什么干涉--
What makes you think you can interfere--?
干涉的人是你们，我们只想阻止你们继续惹是生非
It is you who are interfering. We are simply putting a stop to it.
我们为你们准备的地方
The place we have prepared for you
有充足的原材料
contains sufficient elements for either of you
可以让你们用来制造武器，杀死对手
to construct weapons lethal enough to destroy the other,
这应该正合你们的意图
which seems to be your intention.
决斗的胜者将得以全身而退
The winner of the contest will be permitted to go his way unharmed.
而失败者，将连同他的舰队
The loser, along with his ship,
为了宇宙的和平，将一起被毁灭
shall be destroyed in the interests of peace.
这将会是一场智慧与智慧的较量
The contest will be one of ingenuity against ingenuity,
也是一场蛮力与蛮力的较量
brute strength against brute strength.
而结果将决定一切
The results will be final.
- 等-- - 无需多言
- Just a-- - There will be no discussion.
你们必须服从
It is done.
他消失了
He's gone.
进取号在追击一群外星侵略者的时候
The Enterprise is dead in space,
受到了一股神秘力量的牵制，无法动弹
stopped cold during her pursuit of an alien raider by mysterious forces,
而我则被那股力量送到了
and I have been somehow whisked off the bridge
一颗小行星表面
and placed on the surface of an asteroid,
手无寸铁地面对被麦德隆人称为
facing the captain of the alien ship.
高恩的外星舰长
Weaponless, I face the creature the Metrons called a "Gorn."
一个大型爬虫类
Large, reptilian.
就像多数人一样
Like most humans,
我对爬虫类有一种本能的反感
I seem to have an instinctive revulsion to reptiles.
我必须时刻提醒自己
I must fight to remember
站在我面前的是一个高等生物
that this is an intelligent, highly advanced individual,
和我一样，是一支舰队的舰长
the captain of a starship, like myself.
毫无疑问，是一个聪明的可怕对手
Undoubtedly a dangerously clever opponent.
试过加大引擎功率了吗？
Have you tried overload?
是的，长官，但没有作用
Aye, sir. It does no good.
那试过绕过变压器组
How about bypassing the transformer banks,
直接对推进器供能吗？
feed the impulse engines directly?
也试过了，长官，不行
I tried that, sir. Nothing.
这里是控制室，情况汇报：所有舱板…
Control to bridge, status report: All decks...
通讯官，传感器有检测到
Lieutenant Uhura, have sensors learned anything
这股牵制力量的相关信息吗？
about the nature of the force which holds us here?
对不起，长官，只能确定这股力量
No, sir. They report they definitely emanate
来自前面的行星系统
from that solar system ahead.
那么性质呢？引力、磁力，还是电磁力？
No indication of its composition? Gravimetric? Magnetic? Electronic?
无法确定，长官
Nothing, sir.
我是詹姆士·寇克，星舰进取号的舰长
This is Captain James Kirk, of the starship Enterprise.
找到这份记录的人
Whoever finds this,
请将其转交至星舰司令部
please get it to Starfleet Command.
我正与一个被称作高恩的生物
I am engaged in personal combat
进行一对一的决斗
with a creature apparently called a Gorn.
他非常强壮
He's immensely strong.
对人类来说足以致死的打击
Already, he has withstood attacks from me
对他来说却完全无效
that would have killed a human being.
幸运的是，他虽然强壮，但并不灵活
Fortunately, though strong, he is not agile.
论敏捷和才智，我或许更胜一筹
The agility and, I hope, the cleverness, is mine.
把我们送来这里的麦德隆人说
The Metrons, the creatures that sent us both here,
这个星球的表面
said that the surface of the planet
有足够的原材料
provides the raw material
让我们制造武器
to construct weapons.
但好像并非如此，这里倒是有不少灌木
There's very little here. Scrub brush, rocks,
碎石和矿藏
an abundance of mineral deposits,
至少没有常规的武器
but no weapons in the conventional sense.
不过无论如何，我要尽快找到武器
Still, I need to find one.
赤手空拳地对付一名高恩…
Bare-handed against the Gorn...
…我毫无胜算
...I have no chance.
把第一频道打开以防万一，通讯官
Leave channel one open, lieutenant, just in case.
遵命，长官
Aye, aye sir.
你打算怎么做，史波克？
What are you gonna do, Mr. Spock?
我打算再等等，麦考伊
I'm going to wait, doctor.
- 我别无他择 - 那舰长怎么办？
- There's little else I can do. - What about the captain?
如果有办法救他，我一定会去救
If I could help him, I would.
但我没办法
I cannot.
你不是经常按逻辑思考吗？
Now, you're the one that's always talking about logic.
那现在呢？
What about some logic now?
舰长在哪，史波克？
Where is the captain, Mr. Spock?
他就在那，麦考伊
He's out there, doctor.
在那个1000立方秒差大的星球上
Out there somewhere in 1,000 cubic parsecs of space.
我们根本帮不了他
And there is absolutely nothing we can do to help him.
星球表面有大量的钻石
A large deposit of diamonds on the surface.
这也许是宇宙里已知的最硬物质
Perhaps the hardest substance known in the universe.
美丽而棱角分明
Beautifully crystallised and pointed,
但要作为武器还是太小
but too small to be useful as a weapon.
矿石的储备量实在惊人
An incredible fortune in stones.
但我宁愿以此换一把武器
Yet I would trade them all for a hand phaser
或者一根结实的棍子
or a good solid club.
不过麦德隆人说这里有潜在的武器
Yet the Metron said there would be weapons,
需要我来发现
if I could find them.
到底在哪？
Where?
是什么样的武器？
What kind?
联邦星舰进取号呼叫麦德隆人
This is the USS Enterprise calling the Metrons.
我们开放了频道，请回复
Our channels are open. Come in, please.
我们急需和你们谈谈，请回复
We urgently desire a conference. Please answer.
这可能是我最后一次记录了
This may be my last entry.
我已几乎筋疲力竭
I am almost exhausted.
除非我能找到麦德隆人所说的武器
Unless I find the weapon the Metron mentioned,
否则我很快就会被打败
I have very little time left.
这地方遍布硫磺、钻石，肯定会是矿物学家的天堂
Native sulphur, diamonds. This place is a mineralogist's dream.
不过…
Yet...
…硫磺
...there is something
我想到些什么
about sulphur.
但已经很久远了
Something very old, something...
如果我能回忆起来的话…
If only I could remember.
我们的船，引擎，武器
The ship, our engines, our weapons.
全部无法运作，太不可思议了
It's just inconceivable that we are immobilized.
但事实就是如此，麦考伊
But it has happened, doctor.
我们是麦德隆人
We are the Metrons.
你们的舰长快被打败了
Your captain is losing his battle.
如果在你们的文化里有什么习俗
We would suggest you make whatever memorial arrangements,
可以纪念他的话，我们建议你们这么做
if any, which are customary in your culture.
你们的时间不多了
We believe you have very little time left.
以文明之名，我们请求你们
We appeal to you, in the name of civilisation,
结束这场决斗！
put a stop to this!
你们暴力的意图和行为表明了你们的野蛮
Your violent intent and actions demonstrate that you are not civilised.
但我们也并非毫无同情心
However, we are not without compassion.
或许你们对你们的舰长有着情感
It is possible you may have feelings toward your captain.
我们会让你们了解正在发生的一切
So that you will be able to prepare yourself,
好让你们有心理准备
we will allow you to see and hear what is now transpiring.
如果我们能联系到他就好了
If there were only some way we could contact him.
没错，如果可以的话
Yes, indeed, doctor. If only there were.
你看到那些附在岩石上的物质了吗？
You'll notice the substance encrusting that rock.
看到了
Yes.
如果没看错，那应该是硝酸钾
Unless I'm mistaken, it's potassium nitrate.
- 然后呢？ - 没什么，也许
- So? - Perhaps nothing, doctor.
但也有可能是关键
Perhaps everything.
地球人！
Earthling!
舰长！
Captain!
谁？麦德隆人？
Who is this? The Metron?
我是你的对手，地球人
This is your opponent, earthling.
我听到了你所说的一切
I have heard every word you have said.
- 你想怎样？ - 我已经厌倦了追逐
- All right. What do you want? - I weary of the chase.
你别再躲了
Wait for me.
我会让你死得痛快
I shall be merciful and quick.
- 就像在塞斯图斯三号一样？ - 你们侵犯了我们！
- Like you were at Cestus III? - You were intruding!
你们在我们的领地里建立了哨站
You established an outpost in our space.
你们屠杀了手无寸铁的人类
You butchered helpless human beings.
我们只是在消灭入侵者
We destroyed invaders as I shall destroy you.
那是真的吗？
Can that be true?
真正的侵略者是我们？
Was Cestus III an intrusion on their space?
的确有可能
It may well be possible, doctor.
我们对银河系的那块区域所知不多
We know very little about that section of the galaxy.
那犯错的可能是我们
Then we could be in the wrong.
是的
Perhaps.
最好让外交官来定夺
That is something best decided by diplomats.
那些高恩可能只是在保护他们自己
The Gorn simply might have been trying to protect themselves.
是的
Yes.
有意思
Fascinating.
很好
Good.
他知道了
He knows, doctor.
他想明白了
He has reasoned it out.
是的
Yes.
- 是的 - 怎么了，史波克？
- Yes. - What is it, Spock?
是一项发明，麦考伊
An invention, doctor.
先加入硝酸钾
First potassium nitrate,
然后，如果他能找到硫磺和木炭
and now if he can find some sulphur and a charcoal deposit
或者煤
or ordinary coal.
他在干什么？
What's he doing?
钻石，已知的最硬物质
Diamonds, the hardest known substance.
如果能被足够的力推动
Impelled by sufficient force,
可以成为强大的投射武器
they would make formidable projectiles.
什么力？
What force?
回忆一下基础化学
Recall your basic chemistry, doctor.
- 火药 - 舰长
- Gunpowder. - Captain,
面对现实吧
let us be reasonable.
你已经输了
You have lost.
放弃吧
Admit it to yourself.
别再逃了
Stop running.
煤
Coal.
他能成功吗？
Can he do it?
就看时间够不够了
If he has the time, doctor.
就看时间了
If he has the time.
不
No.
不，我不会杀你
No, I won't kill you.
或许你只是出于自卫目的
Maybe you thought you were protecting yourself
攻击了我们的岗哨
when you attacked the outpost.
不，我不会杀他！
No, I won't kill him!
听到了吗？
Do you hear?
你们要到别处去找乐子了
You'll have to get your entertainment someplace else.
你是麦德隆人？
You're a Metron?
我的外表让你感到意外了吗，舰长？
Does my appearance surprise you, captain?
你看起来还像个孩子
You seem more like a boy.
以你们地球年龄算，我已经差不多1500岁了
I am approximately 1,500 of your Earth years old.
你让我感到了意外，舰长
You surprise me, captain.
- 什么意外？ - 你放过了你的对手
- How? - By sparing your helpless enemy,
即使他可能并不会放过你
who surely would have destroyed you,
你的所为体现了高尚的仁慈
you demonstrated the advanced trait of mercy,
我们并没有想到你会拥有这种特质
something we hardly expected.
我们看到了你们种族的希望
We feel that there may be hope for your kind.
所以不会消灭你们
Therefore, you will not be destroyed.
否则就太野蛮了
It would not be civilised.
- 那么那个高恩呢？ - 我把他送回星舰了
- What happened to the Gorn? - I sent him back to his ship.
如果你喜欢
If you like,
我可以消灭他
I shall destroy him for you.
不，不用了
No, that won't be necessary.
我们可以交流
We can talk,
- 或许可以达成协议 - 很好，舰长
- maybe reach an agreement. - Very good, captain.
我在你身上看到了希望
There is hope for you.
或许，几千年以后
Perhaps, in several thousand years,
我们的种族会相遇并且达成共识
your people and mine shall meet to reach an agreement.
你们仍残留着野蛮的本性
You are still half savage,
但还有希望
but there is hope.
我们准备好之后会联系你们的
We will contact you when we are ready.
舰长！
Captain!
- 没什么事吧？ - 不知道
- Are you all right? - I don't know.
不知道
I don't know.
好了，各就各位
All right, everybody, back to your posts.
我们离开这里
Let's get out of here.
- 舰长 - 怎么了，苏鲁？
- Captain. - Mr. Sulu?
原本应该在那边的天狼星、老人星和阿尔坎尼星
It's impossible, but there's Sirius over there when it should be here,
现在在这边，太不可思议了
and Canopus and Arcanis.
我们--
We're--
瞬间穿越了银河系
All of a sudden, we're clear across the galaxy.
与我们的所在…我是说，之前的所在…
Five hundred parsecs from where we are--
…相距了500秒差距
I mean were-- I mean--
别纠结了，苏鲁
Don't try and figure it out, Mr. Sulu.
设定航向，返回塞斯图斯三号
Just plot a course for us back to Cestus III.
遵命，长官
Aye, aye, sir.
舰长，在你发射你的原始火炮之后
After you touched off your primitive cannon, captain,
麦德隆人给我们的影像中断了
we lost the picture the Metron was sending us.
- 你们看到下面的情况了吗？ - 是的，大部分
- You saw what happened down there? - Most of it.
我很想知道后来发生了什么
I would be interested in knowing what finally happened.
我们是一支前途光明的种族，史波克
We're a most promising species, Mr. Spock, as predators go.
你知道吗？
Did you know that?
- 我经常对此表示怀疑 - 但我不
- I frequently had my doubts. - I don't.
不会再怀疑了
Not anymore.
或许千年之后，我们会证明这一点
And maybe in a thousand years or so, we'll be able to prove it.
别管了，史波克，我也觉得有点飘渺
Never mind, Mr. Spock. Doesn't make much sense to me either.
把我们带到目的地，苏鲁
Take us back to where we're supposed to be, Mr. Sulu.
- 1级曲速 - 1级曲速
- Warp factor 1. - Warp factor 1.
一千年，舰长？
A thousand years, captain?
那我们还有点时间
Well, that gives us a little time.
本集结束
谢谢观赏
-=TLF字幕組=-
字幕站：http://sub.eastgame.org/
微博：http://t.sina.com.cn/tlfsubs